Reading task An April Fool's Joke
The Noodle Harvest A fool sees not the same tree that a wise
man sees.
William Blake April Fool's Day, or April the 1st, is known
in many countries as a day for playing jokes on others.
It is usually a time when children make fun of each other,
but sometimes other people can get caught in the fun too.
One of the most famous jokes in England took place on British television in 1957.
One of them was called Panorama,
This show explored problems and progress all over the world,
so nobody was surprised when it began with a report on the excellent noodle harvest in south Switzerland.
The reporter showed many noodle trees with the farmers pulling noodles off them
and putting them into baskets.
The people watching were told that they may not have heard of noodles from this part of the world
because noodles were grown as part of small family businesses.
The last two weeks of March are an anxious time for noodle farmers.
There is always a chance of very cold weather spoiling their crop.
They rang the BBC to find out how to grow their own noodle tree.
So it seemed possible to imagine that noodles grew on trees like apples,
pears and nuts.
So they were shocked to find the next day that they had all believed an April Fool’s joke.
Even today the report of the noodle harvest is remembered as one of the best April Fool’s jokes ever!